Skills

Azure Cloud Technologies,

Azure DevOps

C# | Asp.Net Core

Angular | TypeScript

NodeJs | JavaScript

Sql Server | MongoDb

Git | GitHub

Xamarin / Ionic for mobile

Qualifications

BCom (Informatics) 2004 University of South Africa

Over 20 years of industry experience developing software solutions.

Info / Contact

+27 (0)60 840 7793

allen@codestream.co.za

Please see my personal and company websites for more details on my skills and experience.

www.codestream.co.za

www.allenfirth.info

Online Profiles

LinkedIn

GitHub

Allen Firth

Architect / Developer

Profile

I am a full stack developer specialising in Azure, Angular, Typescript, C# and SQL Server

I have over <u>20 years of industry experience</u> developing software solutions and leading development teams for large corporates and small start-ups.

I have extensive experience in object orientated architecture, systems design and development and coding practices such as TDD, agile and XP.

I have been exposed to various industries and sectors as well as to all aspects of the software development lifecycle from project conception through analysis, design and implementation and finally, to deployment, maintenance and support of the final product.

Experience

2017 - Current, CodeStream

I've recently completed a **fully remote** role as a **full stack developer** building an Exposure reporting tool for **Anglo American** in the **UK** with live intraday trades using <u>Angular, C#, Asp.NET Core, SignalR and Azure SQL Synapse</u>

I built the Vendor master data management system for **The SPAR Group** using <u>Angular and C# APIs</u>. I was instrumental in development of SPAR's central DataLake reporting database (**SQL Server**) which I later migrated to the **Azure Cloud** using **Azure Data Factory** and **Azure Synapse**.

I've worked **remotely** on a live data processing system for **Chelsea Football Club** in the **UK**, receiving, analysing and processing player GPS, acceleration and speed data being fed live into an **Azure** processing pipeline using **Azure EventHub**, **Azure Functions** and **Azure Sql Server**.

I've worked **remotely** for **CashRewards** in **Australia** building their new Customer Coupon Management site using **Angular**.

I've worked **remotely** for **PROFiltr** in the **UK** bringing their online solution for small bookkeeping companies to completion using **AngualrJS**, **NodeJS and MongoDB**

2014 - 2017, SMEasy (CTO, Architect and Developer)

I was CTO for a small FinTech start-up operating out of <u>Durban, South Africa</u>. SMEasy provided an easy-to-use online accounting package for small to medium enterprises.

I was instrumental in redirecting the architecture and technology choices of the product as well as leading and directing a near re-write of the system using modern frameworks and introducing cutting edge development practises to the development team. SMEasy was developed using **Angular**, **C#**, **Asp.Net** and **Azure SQL Server** and Azure DevOps.

2008 - 2014, London United Kingdom, Various contracts

I spent six and a half years plying my trade as a sought-after software developer in **London**. I gained experience working with top talent in large corporate environments such as <u>Man Investments</u>, <u>BritInsurance</u> and <u>Freshfields Bruckhaus Deringer</u>. I spent the last three years in London working for <u>Digiterre</u> on various projects for the likes of <u>EDF</u> and <u>M&G Asset Management</u>.